<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Renato Fialho</title>
    <link>https://www.renatofialho.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Renato Fialho</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 21:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.renatofialho.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop writing java boilerplate code</title>
      <link>https://www.renatofialho.com/posts/stop-writing-java-boilerplate-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.renatofialho.com/posts/stop-writing-java-boilerplate-code/</guid>
      <description>How many time did you already lose writing boilerplate code in Java? Or generating those in your IDE?
A simple POJO has as least getters, setters, constructors, toString, equals, hashCode and that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of code!
Other programming languages such as Scala and Kotlin provides dynamic access to properties without no extra boilerplate code, but there&amp;rsquo;s a solution for Java? Yes
Project Lombok  Project Lombok is a java library that automatically plugs into your editor and build tools, spicing up your java.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to put your sideproject online with less than $1</title>
      <link>https://www.renatofialho.com/posts/how-sideproject-less-1-dollar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.renatofialho.com/posts/how-sideproject-less-1-dollar/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
So, if you are like me, an enthusiast of development, new languages or new frameworks, there&amp;rsquo;s a high chance that you have a sideproject waiting to be kicked off, and probably because of laziness, lack of time or lack of money, you never put it into production.
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, that happens very often.
This post is focused on helping with the main reason which developers are resistant on putting those projects in production: Money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porque devemos investir enquantos jovens</title>
      <link>https://www.renatofialho.com/posts/porque-devemos-investir-jovens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.renatofialho.com/posts/porque-devemos-investir-jovens/</guid>
      <description>A diferença entre esperar para investir em sua aposentadoria e começar hoje pode ser brutal, e o culpado disso tem nome e sobrenome, juros compostos, que pode parecer um termo intimidador, mas que pode ser seu melhor amigo para um futuro financeiro estável e tranquilo.
  Se você consegue ler em inglês e leu o about, sabe que um dos assuntos que eu mais me interesso e procuro conhecer um pouco mais é sobre finanças e investimentos, além de que o meu e da torcida do galo sonho é fazer o dinheiro trabalhar para mim em algum momento da vida.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://www.renatofialho.com/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.renatofialho.com/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone!
As part of learning new technologies and new things, i&amp;rsquo;m bringing this blog back to life using Hugo , i&amp;rsquo;ll try to bring posts and news mainly about finance, technology, project management and other subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.renatofialho.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.renatofialho.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Renato Fialho, a Full Stack Developer based in Stockholm , Sweden.
Currently, i work as a Senior Software Engineer for Klarna where i develop mainly backend services using Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, Apache Kafka and other distributed systems technologies.
I worked as a Software Engineer for Hotmart in Belo Horizonte - MG, where i developed and maintained backend services using Java and Kotlin, Spring and J2EE, MySQL, Terraform, AWS (ECS, EKS, S3, SQS, SNS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.renatofialho.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.renatofialho.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>       Submit Form  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks</title>
      <link>https://www.renatofialho.com/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.renatofialho.com/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for your contact! I&amp;rsquo;ll answer as soon as possible.
If you want, follow me on my social networks @renatobh or on github @fialhorenato</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>